Finding Aid for Robert Lewis Williams papers, 1929-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert Lewis Williams papers 1929-1970
Williams, Robert Lewis, 1903-
9 linear feet
86299 Aa 2
University of Michigan administrator; reports and other data relating to the budgetary and physical operation of University of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Robert L. Williams (donor no. 4450 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Robert Lewis Williams served the University of Michigan in various administrative capacities: as assistant registrar, 1936-1945, assistant dean of faculties, 1951-1958, and administrative dean in the office of the Vice President of Academic Affairs.
The Williams collection consists entirely of reports, studies, and other documentation accumulated in his role as University of Michigan administrator. This includes notebooks containing reports and other data relating to the budgetary and physical operation of University of Michigan; reports with information on the financial status and characteristics of University faculty members; and statistical reports relating to students attending the University.
Subjects:
Students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Universities and colleges--Michigan.; University of Michigan--Administration.; University of Michigan--Campus.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Finance.; University of Michigan. Provost.; University of Michigan. Office of the Registrar.; University of Michigan--Students.; University of Michigan. Vice President for Academic Affairs.
- University of Michigan reports and studies
  - Academic Personnel -- Compensation Notebooks, 1929-1930 and 1946-1964 (Box 1)
  - Salary Ranges Notebook, 1929-1954 (Box 2)
  - Academic Personnel -- Characteristics Notebooks, 1945-1962 (Box 2)
  - Physical Plant and its Use Notebooks, 1941-1961 (Box 2)
  - Budgetary and Fiscal Analyses Notebooks, 1950-1959 (Box 3)
  - Budgetary and Fiscal Analyses Notebooks, 1959-1963 (Box 4)
  - University Relations to State, Nation, and other Institutions Notebooks, 1929-1930 and 1948-1963 (Box 4)
  - Research Reports, 1952-1960 (Box 5)
  - Operations Analysis Notebooks, 1939-1962 (Box 5)
  - Student Body Notebooks, 1941-1958 (Box 6)
  - Profile of the University of Michigan, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Scholarships, etc. Notebook, 1940-1952 (Box 7)
  - Control Data (Box 7)
  - Special Service Positions (Box 7)
  - Flint College and Dearborn Campus materials (Box 7)
  - Coordinating Committee for Veterans Service, 1944 (Box 8)
  - Grade distributions (Box 8)
  - Salary Data (Box 8)
  - University Senate (Box 8)
  - Industrial College of the Armed Forces, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Administration Information Sheets (Box 8)
  - Advisory Board on University Policies Supporting Papers, 1931-1944 (Box 8)
  - School of Music Faculty Record, 1948-1949 (Box 8)
  - Report of Facilities Submitted to the Federal Security Agency, Office of Education, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Report of Facilities Submitted to the Navy, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Publications of the Office of Educational Investigations (Box 9)